# **BECON DANIEL O.**

Mr., Engr, Dev

283, Ifite Road, Awka, Anambra +2348037026969 daffydanni@yahoo.com

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Web Developer, Data Analyst with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and services industry. I am Skilled in Communication, Customer Relationship Management (CRM), Management, Microsoft Excel, and Engineering. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Engineering - BE focused on metallurgical/material engineering from Nnamdi Azikiwe University.

#### **AREAS OF EXPERTISE**

- Frontend Developer
- Excel
- SQL
- Python
- Bootstrap
- ReactJS Developer

- Tableau
- Material Engineering
- Performance Management
- Team Building and Leadership
- Complex Problem-solving Abilities
- Interpersonal Communication Skills

**Technical Skills:** Microsoft Office Suite, MS Excel Proficiency, Structured Query Language (MySQL), Python, Tableau, React, JavaScript, HTML and CSS.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Bonitas Group LTD, Awka Web Developer

Jan. 2022- Jan. 2023

- Bringing UI to life.
- Maintaining code base in the development process.
- Developing an effective and reusable code base.
- Monitoring the company's website performance using established corporate business performance metrics.
- Providing leadership in the development of staff policies, training, and performance measurement.

## **Key Accomplishments**

- Successfully set up the frontend design for the GVE project.
- Involvement in the frontend design for the HSE App.
- Finished a course on Coursera for Frontend Development

# Stanel Group PLC, Awka Customer Associate

Mar. 2018-Jan. 2021

- Facilitated positive relationships with customers and clients.
- Monitored the implementation of discharging and offloading of products.
- Optimized the handling of cash and deposit relationships and initiated appropriate strategies to enhance cash positioning.

- Implemented a reliable work process to help customers and colleagues have a good working environment.
- Ensured appropriate financial risk, accounting, and procedures of the company.

## **Key Accomplishments**

• Successfully developed a culture of accountability in managing the business by creating an accountability reputation for the company.

## Arizona Digital LTD, Lagos

## **Office Assistant**

Jun. 2012-Nov. 2014

- Performing general office tasks such as filing, phones, and photocopying.
- Managing calendars, scheduling appointments, and coordinating meetings.
- Creating and formatting documents, such as reports and presentations.
- Involved actively in the strategy phase and the eventual kick-off of the product to clients.
- Providing customer service, including responding to inquiries and handling complaints.

## **Key Accomplishments**

- Advanced my Microsoft skills.
- My organizational abilities improved.

#### **OTHER EXPERIENCES**

Industrial Training (Field Engineer); Swiss Biostat Group, Lagos.

July 2019–Dec. 2019
Sales Personnel; Chi Limited Plc, Lagos

Nov2011– April 2011

## **EDUCATION**

BSc. in Metallurgical and Material Engineering, Nnamdi Azikiwe	2021
University, Awka	
SSCE.: Command Day Secondary School Oshodi, Lagos	2011

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Coursera; Frontend Development course by Meta 2022

#### **REFERENCES**

Available on request